不正視聴!?
The world will know real pain.
本当の痛みを世界へ知らしめ➡
The fear instilled by that pain
would prevent wars.
その痛みの恐怖で戦いを抑止し➡
世界を 安定と平和へ導くのだ。
And the world will be on the road
to stability and peace.
But that kind of peace...
(ナルト)だからって そんな平和…。
そんなの嘘っぱちじゃねえかよ。
It's nothing but a fake!
人間は
そんなに賢い生き物ではない。
Humans are not
the most intelligent of creatures.
そうでもしなければ➡
This is the only way
that peace can be achieved.
平和を作れないのだ。
やがて その痛みも➡
And after several decades,
that pain too will
eventually fade with time.
何十年と時が経てば 癒えていく。
抑止力は低下し➡
It will no longer be a deterrent
そして また人々は争い➡
and humanity will begin
to battle once more.
今度は
自分たちで尾獣兵器を使い➡
This time, they themselves will use
the Tailed Beast Weapon
本当の痛みを再確認する。
against one another
and reconfirm what true pain is.
(長門)そして また
一時の平和が訪れる。
And then peace will be
restored again, for a time.
この終わりなき
憎しみの連鎖の流れのなかに➡
In the course of
this endless cycle of hatred...
痛みにより
一時の平和を生み出すこと。
Pain will give rise to momentary peace.
それが 俺の願いだ。
That is my dream.
ゴホッ ゴホッ…。
(小南)長門…
あまり無理をしないで。
Nagato...try not to push yourself.
もう ずいぶんチャクラを使ってる。
You've already spent so much chakra.
平和は目の前だ。
Peace is right within our grasp.
((いいか！ 俺はぜってぇ➡
Now get this!
I'm absolutely gonna
be named the Hokage!
火影の名前を
もらうんだってばよ！
You just watch, everyone!
お前ら 今に見てろ！
That boy.
やだ あの子。
あの子は…。
He's...
The awful Nine-Tails...
忌々しい九尾の…。
Hey, that topic is taboo.
ちょっと それ禁句。
(ヒナタ)キュウビ？ キュウビって何？
Nine-Tails? What's the Nine-Tails?
(コウ)ヒナタ様は そんなこと
知らなくても いいんですよ。
It's something you do not
need to know, Lady Hinata.
(でも あの子には
近づかないでくださいね))
But...you must not go near that boy.
《ヒナタ : ナルト君…》
Naruto...
お前は 俺の平和を
嘘っぱちだと言うが➡
You argue that my vision
of peace is a fake.
But in this cursed world,
there is nothing more fictional
この呪われた世界で
人と人がわかり合う平和ほど➡
than a peace where people can
truly understand one another.
虚構なものはない。
((自来也 : 人が本当の意味で
理解し合える時代が来ると➡
But I have faith that
there will come a time when people
can truly understand one another.
(わしは信じとる))
エロ仙人は 人が本当の意味で➡
Pervy Sage believed that the day
would come
when people truly understand
one another.
理解し合える時代が
来ると信じてた。
You're wrong!
お前のは違う。
Empty words...
口だけだな。
What can you do when you can't
even back up your answer?
答えを示せないお前に
何ができる？
All you are good for...
お前のできることは…。
九尾の力を➡
-...is giving me the power
俺に差し出すことぐらいだ。
of the Nine-Tails.
言ったはずだ。
Like I told you earlier...
your death will lead to peace.
お前の死が 平和へ繋がると。
Confessions
((ヒナタは➡
I want to grow up to
be a great ninja...
父のように強くて➡
strong like Father and kind like Mother!
母のように優しい➡
すごい忍になりたいです。
ヒアシ様の厳しさは➡
Lord Hiashi is very strict
それだけ ヒナタ様に
期待されているからなんです。
because he has high hopes for you.
One day, you will enter
this Academy too, Lady Hinata.
いつか ヒナタ様も
ここに入学なさるのですよ。
大丈夫かな？
I wonder if I'll make it...
Of course you will.
So you must do your best.
ええ もちろんですよ。
がんばりましょう。
That boy...
あの子…。
Lady Hinata, please don't associate
with him.
ヒナタ様 あの子には
関わらないでくださいね。
えっ どうして？
But why?
修業の時間です 戻りましょう。
It's time for your training.
Let's go back.
(あ…))
ナルト君…。
Naruto...
(ネジ)あ…。
(ガイ)どうした？ ネジ。
What's wrong, Neji?
(ネジ)あれは自来也様の口寄せ蛙。
That's Lord Jiraiya's Summoning Frog.
What?!
なに!?
(いのいち)ペイン本体は➡
So the real Pain will be
at the highest spot,
この木ノ葉近くの一番高い場所に
いるってことになる。
somewhere near the Leaf Village.
All right, let's search every single site
that is at high altitude!
(シカク)よし！ なら高い場所を
しらみ潰しに捜索するぞ。
最低でもツーマンセルで
行動したほうがいいだろう。
Work in teams with
at least two people per cell.
敵の本体を見つけたとしても➡
And if you find the real Pain,
do not engage him carelessly.
うかつに手出しはするな。
Try to include Sensory-Type ninja
in the search teams.
(シカマル)なるべく 感知タイプの忍を➡
捜索隊に加えてくれ。
そのほうが早い。
It'll be faster.
(シカク)わかった。
All right.
Shikamaru, stay here with Shiho
and wait for word from us.
シカマル お前はシホと
ここで連絡を待て。
I guess I have no choice
since I can't move.
悔しいけど そうなるな。
動けねえんじゃよ。
Okay, Katsuyu.
(いのいち)
よし カツユ。 このことを➡
Get word of this to every
able survivor in the village.
里の生存者で
動ける者には連絡してくれ。
里の者に 協力してもらう。
We'll need their help.
Yes, I understand.
(カツユ)はい 了解しました。
((私は 父上のように強く
母上のように優しい➡
I want to become a great ninja...
strong like Father and
kind like Mother.
立派な忍になりたいです。
ハッ！ ハーッ！
父上のように強く。
A great ninja...
ヤッ！ ヤーッ！
立派な忍に。
strong like Father...
ヤーッ！
Lady Hinata!
(コウ)ヒナタ様！
Hey you!
おい お前！
(ヒナタ)ごめんなさい！
I-I'm sorry!
あっ コイツ 日向家の子じゃねえの？
Hey...she's the Hyuga kid!
そうだよ この眼！
あのネジのいとこだぜ きっと！
Yeah, she's got the eyes!
She must be that Neji's cousin.
コイツも性格悪いんだろうな！
She's probably cocky too.
She thinks she's better than us
'cuz of her family and talent!
名門で才能あるからってよ
すっげえ偉そうにしやがって！
私 別に そんなこと…。
I-I'm not like that at all...
あっ テメエ！
Hey you!
ちゃんと謝りもせずに
逃げようなんて 最低なヤツ！
Trying to run off without saying
you're really sorry?
What a jerk!
Don't let her get away with that!
許せねえよ！
おい 謝れよ！
ちゃんと謝れよ！
Hey, say you're sorry.
Apologize nicely.
謝れよ！
Say you're sorry!
ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry...
弱ぇよ！
もっと ちゃんと謝れ！
Not good enough!
Say it like you mean it!
Apologize!
謝れっつうの！
(ごめんなさい ごめんなさい
ごめんなさい！))
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
ぐっ！
《ペインのチャクラが入ってくる》
I can feel...
Pain's chakra coming inside...
急所は外して浅くしてある。
I've avoided any vital spots
and kept them shallow.
これで お前は
自分の意思では動けない。
But you will no longer be able
to move on your own.
(シマ)しっかりせい 小僧！
Snap out of it, Lad!
(シマ)ソイツが何言おうが お前は
聞く耳をもったらいけん！
No matter what he says,
you must not listen!
お前は予言の子じゃ！
この世の救世主じゃ！
You're the Child of Prophecy!
The savior of this world!
自来也の小僧も父ちゃんも
それを信じて命をかけたんじゃ！
Jiraiya-boy and Pa sacrificed themselves
because they believed that!
じゃけん
お前が負けることは許されん！
So you cannot lose!
こんなとこで お前が
くたばったら ウチが許さん！
If you give up now,
I won't forgive you!
うるさいカエルだ。
テメエ！
Noisy frog.
Bastard!
そろそろ お前を連れていく。
I guess I'll be taking you now...
はっ！
ヒナタ様！
Lady Hinata!
How cruel...
《ひどい… この杭で
ナルト君の動きを 封じているのね》
Restricting Naruto's movement
with those poles.
ナルト君には もう手は出させない！
I won't let you hurt Naruto anymore!
増援か。
Reinforcements?
Why'd you come out here?!
なんで出てきたんだってばよ！
Get away quickly! You're no match...
早く逃げろ
お前じゃ ソイツには…。
I know.
これは 私のひとりよがり。
I'm just being...selfish.
何言ってんだ！
What are you talking about?!
Don't put yourself in danger like this!
そんなんで こんな危ねえとこ
出てくるんじゃねえ！
ここに立っているのは
私の意志。
I'm here because I want to be.
今度は 私がナルト君を助けるの。
This time...
I'm going to save you, Naruto.
泣いてばかりで 最初から諦めて。
I was always crying,
and giving up before even trying.
I made the wrong turns
so many times...
何度も間違ったところに
行こうとして。
そんな私を ナルト君が➡
But you helped me find my way
and take the correct path, Naruto.
正しいところへ
連れてきてくれたの。
いつも ナルト君を追いかけて
ナルト君に追いつきたくて➡
I always chased after you.
I wanted to catch up to you.
いつだって
ナルト君と一緒に歩きたくて。
I wanted to walk
beside you all the time.
I want to be at your side, always.
いつも ナルト君のところへ…。
ナルト君が 私を変えてくれた。
You changed me, Naruto!
ナルト君の笑顔が 私を救ってくれた。
Your smile is what saved me!
だから ナルト君を守るためなら
死ぬことなんて怖くない！
That's why I'm not afraid to die...
if it means I can protect you!
私は ナルト君が大好きだから。
Because...
I love you, Naruto!
はっ！
何？
What?
キャー!!
ヒナタ！
Hinata!
《ナルト君に近づけない。
I can't get near Naruto...
なんとかしないと！》
I must do something!
《このまま終われない。
I can't let it end like this.
If there's even the slightest chance...
ほんの少しでも
可能性があるなら！》
柔歩双獅拳！
Gentle Step... Twin Lion Fists!
うお～！
うっ！
長門！
Nagato!
Now's my chance!
今だ！
もう一本！
One more time!
キャー！
ヒナタ！
Hinata!
((やめろよ。
Cut it out.
なんだ オメエ。
おい コイツ あれだよ。
What do you want?
Hey, he's the kid!
That one who's always getting
into trouble.
バカないたずらばっかやって
嫌われてる あれじゃん。
The one everyone hates!
Oh, yeah... That guy.
ああ あれか！
あれね。
That guy, huh?
アハハハハ！
俺は あれなんかじゃねえ。
I'm not "that guy"!
俺は うずまきナルト
いずれ 火影になるってばよ！
My name is Naruto Uzumaki!
I'm gonna be the Hokage one day.
覚えとけ！
火影!? ハハハハハ！
Remember that!
- Hokage?!
Are you crazy?
バカじゃねえの！
なに ふかしてんだよ。
That's a bunch of baloney!
頭悪いガキだな。
What a stupid kid!
There's no way an idiot
like you can be one!
オメエみてえなガキが
なれるわけねえじゃん！
フン。
やるか。
Wanna fight?
後悔すんなよ オメエら。
Better not regret it, guys!
あっ その印は…。
What seal is he weaving?
Clone...
分身の…。
まさか。
- No way!
術！
Jutsu!
アハハハハハ！
ひでえ！
That was terrible...
笑わすなよ。
だあ！
Don't make us laugh!
Caught you off guard! How's that?!
油断しやがって どうだ！
I will! I'm absolutely gonna
become the Hokage!
俺はなる
絶対 火影になって➡
お前らなんか
見返してやるってばよ。
And I'll prove you wrong!
コイツ！
なめやがって！
Why you...
Don't take us lightly!
Lady Hinata!
ヒナタ様！
ああ… やべえ！
Run!
ヒナタ様 大丈夫ですか？
Lady Hinata... Are you all right?
この子は…。
This boy...
ヒナタ様 さあ。
Come on, Lady Hinata.
待って この子は 私を…。
Wait... He came to my rescue...
彼とは関わってはいけません。
You must not get involved with him.
(さあ。
でも…))
Let us go.
B-But...
ヒナタ ヒナタ！
Hinata!
おい ヒナタ！
Hey!
Damn it...
Hinata!
ヒナタ！
う… あっ！
やめろ ヒナタ 来るんじゃねえ。
Stop...
Don't come, Hinata.
((俺は逃げねえぞ！))
I'm not running away!
It's impossible to change yourself.
((ネジ : 自分を変えるなんてこと
絶対に…。
Sure she can! Don't go deciding
what a person is like!
(できる！
人のこと勝手に決めつけんな！))
Go, Hinata!
((ヒナタ 頑張れ！))
I always thought you were
so negative, hesitant, and weird.
((暗くって 地味で ウジウジしてて
変なヤツだと思ってた。))
((けど お前みたいなヤツって
結構 好きだってばよ！))
But I kind of like people like you.
I don't understand.
わからない…。
お前ごときの力で なぜ刃向かう？
Why would someone weak
like you try to resist?
なぜ戦う？
Why fight me?
死ぬとわかっているのに…。
Knowing...that you'll die?
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げない！
- I stand by what I say.
それが… 私の忍道だから。
Because that's...my Ninja Way...
ちょうど こんなふうにだったか。
It was just like this...
俺の両親も
お前ら 木ノ葉の忍に➡
My parents were killed
before my very eyes
目の前で殺された。
by ninja from the Hidden Leaf.
愛情があるからこそ
犠牲が生まれ➡
Out of love, sacrifice is born...
憎しみが生まれ➡
Hate is born...
痛みを知ることができる。
and we are able to know pain.
そうだ 痛みを知れ！
Yes... Know pain.
(サクラ)うわっ！
あれは…。
What's that?!
俺が憎いか？
Do you hate me?
What the hell was
that explosion?!
(ナツ)ルーシィ！
俺の声 聞こえてんだろ？
You must all evacuate
as far away as you can!
待ってろよ
ぜってぇ助けっからな。
That is Naruto's Nine-Tails power!
What?!
But a Sealing Jutsu should
have been placed on Naruto!
Hina
(ルーシィ)警告。
刻印が１つ解除された。
残る３つを失えば
所有者は その権利を失う。
ルーシィ しっかりしろ！